Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Eleventh Planet of the Solar System
Commander Hijikata, the ships,
equipment, and personnel are finally ready.
I want you to send them out
for exploration as soon as possible.
That’s a pretty well-grown tree, isn’t it?
It is.
Here you go, Mr. Santa.
Awesome !
No fun without a Christmas tree, don’t you think so ?
I owe you as always, Commander Saito.
That old man was severely injured in the
war against Garmillas, and lost his family, too.
That’s why playing with those kids is all he lives for.
I hope the tree will add an extra touch.
Hmmm ?
What’s wrong, Nagakura ?
Building a good relationship
with the people at a post is…
Never seen a looker like her on base.
She may have arrived on the morning flight.
I know how you feel, but please wait until
the inspection is over, Professor Redrowz.
But that won’t…
It's regulations. Excuse me.
Wait, Commander Hijikata !
This is ridiculous.
…Ancient Archelias Ruins…
He ignored the directive from the Chief of Staff.
I guess that stubborn commander wants to
stay on this remote planet for the rest of his life.
When can I investigate the planet
where the ancient Archelias ruins remain ?
So, that’s the outermost planet of this system ?
It strays from the common planetary
plane because of its unique orbit…
…but an artificial sun ensures the planet’s biological activity.
Then, we will ensure something else.
The usual measures have been taken.
The name of the planet is Telezart…
…a legendary planet whose
civilization has developed to its peak.
The people of the planet benefited from their
ability to convert human will into a physical force.
Just like human imagination is limitless,
the energy from the human soul is infinite.
With unlimited power, they could alter the
shape of a constellation if they chose to do so.
Eventually, they transcended their physical bodies,
and became mental entities.
Then they merged into a single life form
in a dimension beyond human reach.
Her name is Teresa, a goddess who resides between this world and the next, desiring peace for all.
Lieutenant Kodai, this is no fairy tale.
Various interstellar civilizations have literature which proves the existence of Telezart.
All of them more than a thousand years old...
...including the records of those who were called by Teresa.
Called ?
Kodai, the former crew of the
Yamato saw a common vision…
…a vision of the deceased who were close to the crew.
They’re the messengers of Teresa.
Kodai, get on board the Yamato.
Teresa has the insight of space from the beginning to its end,
because she exists in a higher dimension than ours.
Those who’re called by Teresa must fulfill
their duty according to a predetermined fate.
Doctor…
Hmmm ?
…who am I ?
Are you worried because you're the
only one who didn't see a vision ?
I’ve heard a rumor about Kodai.
I’m sure he’s safe.
That’s more like you.
It doesn’t matter who you are.
We know you very well.
You have no doubts when
it comes to believing in Kodai.
That’s who you are.
Right ?
Yes.
Who did you see, Doctor ?
Their ancestors.
Many civilizations have dispatched expeditions, but no one has found the planet Telezart.
They say the planet itself
must be sealed off somehow.
Those coordinates…
They match the direction of the energy
wave which made us see the vision.
Right. You took it as an SOS signal.
Recently, Gatlantis has been
active in that sector of space.
Gatlantis ?
We know little about them.
It’s a powerful military nation, but we don’t
even know where their home planet is located.
If Gatlantis has broken the seal of Telezart…
If so, why is Gatlantis targeting Telezart ?
If you can break the seal and obtain the power of Teresa, you can do anything…
…so the legend says.
It’s probably not a legend.
If Teresa is an entity of a higher order,
she must have the power to do anything in our world.
But that’s…
…just speculation, of course.
But the fact that the Yamato's
crew has been chosen is real.
Chosen ?
It’s not Earth, nor Garmillas, it's your crew.
If so, I think I know the reason why.
Keyman, take him to Earth.
You know where, don’t you ?
Yes.
Kodai...
...witness the truth of Earth with your own eyes.
Restricted Area Somewhere on Earth
What...is that ?
It’s going to be a 1-hour tour.
Your body won't be able to
withstand more than that.
Let’s go.
Some say this place suffers from Reverse Syndrome.
Reverse…?
This planet was devastated
by Garmillas meteorite bombs.
So how was it restored ?
By the Cosmo Reverse…
Unknown technology tends to have
side effects, but this is beyond ridiculous.
A human can't even withstand
ten minutes without these scale cylinders.
T...that’s…
Where are we ?
This is the dark side of Earth,
hidden behind its beautifully restored nature.
It’s a singularity created by the Cosmo Reverse.
How…?
How could this have happened ?
It took five years to understand
the nature of the Reverse Syndrome.
Ten years to build the dock.
"Time Fault…"
That’s what it’s called by those who know the truth.
Time Fault…?
One day outside equals ten days here.
Cosmo Reverse created this anti-gravity singularity, which has distorted time inside this cave.
This massive military factory took 30 years
to construct, while only three years passed outside.
You must have wondered how the
Andromeda was constructed so quickly.
Without this place, a fleet of ships with wave motion guns and the restoration of Earth would not have happened.
Restoration ?!
You can't call this restoration !
The joint fleet and military alliance…
The problem isn't yours alone.
Those are Garmillas ships.
The Earth government sold the usage
rights of the Time Fault to Garmillas.
"Sold"…?!
In exchange for several colony planets that
we haven’t figured out how to make use of…
…including its abundant resources,
and the colonists who live there.
Garmillas can't continue its expansion,
while Earth steers a course to greater strength.
The true meaning of the words “politics” and “economy” is shared throughout the universe, isn't it ?
Is this the future the Yamato
and its difficult journey created ?
Promise me to never repeat our folly.
I promise.
Kodai’s back from the moon.
Do you mean…
Yeah, he now knows about the Time Fault.
I knew this could happen when he went
to see a high-ranking Garmillas official.
Earth will continue building a
fleet of wave motion gun vessels.
That's the reality.
Commander, I’m very sorry for this outcome.
Only because you stood up for us…
I must go, but you have to hold your ground.
Now that Hijikata has been forced out,
even if we don’t make a move, someone will.
If so…
If so…?!
If so, what ?
I'll re-install the wave motion gun on the Yamato myself.
Kodai, don’t !
Kodai !
Kodai, let me get to the point.
I can't authorize your expedition to Telezart.
Why not, Chief ?
Are you going to ignore the call for help ?
Chief, could you say the same to Captain Okita ?
What are we supposed to protect ?
What about the promise to Iscandar ?
Building such a large-scale wave
motion fleet by using the Time Fault…
Such a thing doesn't exist !
Whatever you saw,
this decision can't be overturned.
You're dismissed.
Kodai…
Mr. Sanada, what was our journey for ?
Where is the Earth we wanted to restore ?
I feel like I’m going to forget.
Kodai…
Welcome back.
Sorry for not contacting you.
We've all verified the Time Fault data Mr. Sanada sent.
When did you get this information ?
Hijikata told us to stay in the
heart of this matter when he left.
I accepted the offer of refitting the Yamato
in order to gather as much information as possible.
Although we’ve discovered the existence of the
Time Fault, we can’t change the course of the tide.
In the end, we lost.
What do you mean ?
All of the Yamato's crew have
been reassigned as of today.
Don't worry.
It's not because of your complaint.
The brass will never understand how we feel.
Earth was supposed to have been saved
by our great journey three years ago.
But today's Earth is…
This can't be right.
Those who are no longer with
us had something to say to us.
A calamity is about to happen somewhere in the universe.
There are no words to describe
what we're being forced to feel.
The current Earth government
doesn't want to understand it.
They can only see the reality right before their eyes…
…to survive and protect the Earth's sovereignty.
But wouldn't that lead to the wrong future ?
Right now…
Right now, I'm too embarrassed
to pay respect to the deceased !
Only the Yamato crew has received Teresa’s message.
I want to go to Telezart !
Will you help me ?!
Kodai, let's go.
There's no place for the Yamato on today's Earth.
That's why we must find out the truth
to stop this mistaken future from happening.
That's exactly what we must do now.
It's the destiny of those who survived on the Yamato.
Mr. Sanada…
I’m sure Captain Okita will guide us.
That’s right. Let’s go.
Right.
Let’s go on the Yamato.
Let's do it !
I'll do my best !
We're not wrong !
Screw HQ.
I'll contact everyone.
Nagakura, have some.
What the...?
We're going to be busy.
I'll have to go get some extra clothes.
Yuki, I want you to hide somewhere.
What do you mean ?
This trip is different from before.
What we're doing is treason.
So, what ?
You just want me to stay on Earth ?
Why do you treat me
different from everyone else ?
Yuki…
Is it because I didn't see the vision,
or because Telezart didn't call me ?
I lost my memory because of the accident,
so I can only recall things from the last four years.
I don't want to drag you into this.
We really don't know anything about each other, do we ?
Yuki, trust me.
I’ll come home, so…
Yuki !
Yuki.
Episode 3
Astonishing Legacy of the Cosmo Reverse
Tawamureru yuragu tsuki no kagami
The reflection of the moon is blurry and capricious
Kodai Susumu:
Mori Yuki:
Shima Daisuke:
Sanada Shiro:
Nanbu Yasuo:
Aihara Yoshikazu:
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Sado Sakezo:
Niimi Kaoru:
Enomoto Isami:
Yamazaki Susumu:
Misaki Yuria:
Ono Daisuke
Kuwashima Houko
Suzumura Kenichi
Otsuka Hochu
Akabane Kenji
Kokubun Masato
Mugihito
Chiba Shigeru
Hisakawa Aya
Tsuda Kenjiro
Tsuchida Hiroshi
Uchida Aya
Saito Hajime:
Nagakura Shiori:
Robert Redrowz:
Okita Juzo:
Hijikata Ryu:
Todou Heikuro:
Barrel:
Keyman:
Cosmodart:
Starsia:
Tim:
Subordinate:
Eldar:
Iry:
Touchi Hiroki
Amagai Kazusa
Hashi Takaya
Sugao Takayuki
Ishizuka Unsho
Kojima Toshihiko
Terasoma Masaki
Kamiya Hiroshi
Kawai Tomoya
Inoue Kikuko
Fukumatsu Shinya
Yano Masaaki
Kitagawa Rina
Aoki Shiki
Kokoro tokasu yuubina kami no itazura
Graceful God's mischief mesmerizes my heart
Uchi ni himeta awai omoide ni
There's a faint memory hidden within
Iki wo fukikomu no michite yukumade
Breathe life into it until it's full
Hibiku anata no mune no kodou wo
I hear a heartbeat echoing through
Watashi hitori janai
I am not alone
Saewataru sora ni inori
I pray to the wide open sky
Atarashii ichinichi no maku ga aketeyuku
The curtain opens on a brand new day
Preview
I’m afraid of myself for resorting
to using the wave motion gun.
Is this the only option left ?
I won't allow any killing.
We must launch the Yamato no matter what.
Kodai, show your resolve.
Yamato, take off.
Episode 04
Take off for the Unknown!